Maira Prado

UX Designer

Contact

(929)766-9535 mairapradol@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/maira-prado www.mairaprado.com

Summary

Experienced **UX Designer with over 4 years of direct industry experience and 8 years as a Research Analyst**, offering a comprehensive blend of design and analytical expertise. Pioneered the transformation of the ordering experience for Transfer and Edge Appliances at Google Cloud, catalyzing a sales surge and facilitating self-service capabilities across 31 countries. Additionally, served as the main designer of a crucial Google Cloud feature, adeptly bridging a significant market gap.

Experience

UX Designer | Google | 2021-2023

- Designed the end-to-end self-service experience for Google Cloud's two appliances, driving a significant increase in sales and enabling self-service functionality across 31 countries.
- Created prototypes for team feedback and to facilitate usability testing.
- Collaborated across four teams to design and launch a key feature for Google Cloud, ensuring seamless integration and product functionality.
- Bolstered engineering by supporting implementation, participating in two pre-launch bug hunts, and ensuring postlaunch product success.
- Enhanced Google's educational content by conducting user research and implementing strategies to improve accessibility for individuals with dyscalculia; potentially benefiting up to 6% of the global population.
- Created two surveys to refine Google's internal educational materials, enhancing content quality and engagement.
- Presented about dyscalculia to two teams to create awareness and also delivered a presentation at a Google conference, reaching an audience of 50 people and furthering inclusivity efforts.

Product Designer | Freelance | 2020-2024

- Ensuring the creation of accessible websites by adhering to WCAG guidelines.
- Using user surveys, personas, competitive analysis, and user stories to gather data and inform design decisions based on user feedback.
- Creating user flows, diagrams, sketches, wireframes, brand identities, style guides, mockups, and prototypes, and conducting usability testing to verify that designs precisely meet user needs.
- Providing expert consulting services in UX design, enhancing usability and design quality across multiple platforms, significantly improving user satisfaction and digital presence.

Tools & Methodologies

Figma, Sketch, InVision, Adobe XD, Miro, UsabilityHub, GitHub, Atom, User Flows, Wireframes, Mockups, Prototypes, Usability Testing, User Personas, User Survey, Competitive Analysis, Card Sorting, User Stories, A/ B Test, HTML, CSS.

Education

Google | 2021-2022 UX Design Specialization

Google | 2022

Accessibility Foundation Certification (FAKC)

IAAP | 2021

Certified Professional in Accessibility Core Competencies (CPACC)

Bloc | 2019-2020 Design Program

Tuiuti | 2005-2011 Law School

Community contribution

- Delivered a presentation at Google's Accessibility Internal Conference on 'Getting Started with Designing for Accessibility'.
- Presented at Google's UX conference on equitable UX design careers, emphasizing the inclusion of diverse backgrounds.
- Played a pivotal role in volunteer efforts such as the Code Nation Hackathon and robotics workshops, supporting 400 underrepresented youth in tech.
- Coordinated the Day of the Dead celebration at Google, boosting workplace diversity and cultural awareness among over 300 employees.
- Serving as a UX and coding mentor for over 4 years, guiding and supporting emerging designers in the field.